I forgive them with all my heart as I ask God to forgive me.
[off camera]: The verdict is clear. You're guilty of high treason.
But let them remember that I struggled for the Métis,
for the people of Manitoba and the North-West.
[off camera]: There can be no excuse for what you have done...
The Métis are not birds.
[off camera]: the law requires you to answer for it.
We have a right to God's lands.
Insane? I have battled an insane and irresponsible government.
[off camera]: You will be taken to the place appointed for your execution.
Perhaps I am a prophet -- I suffered enough.
[off camera]: hanged by the neck until you are dead.
I struggled not only for myself,
but for the rights of my people, the Métis.
Métis woman: Louis Riel led our Métis nation,
and he gave us hope and strength and pride.
Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.